Ishwar Sawale

NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING & COMPUTER VISION · DEEP LEARNING & MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

★ ishwarsawale.github.io | ② ishwarsawale | ➤ courses | ⑤ ishwarsawale

Summary_

I am a Software Engineer working on Machine Learning & Data Science algorithms for 4.4+ Years. I am currently working with Indegene Inc on research and development for healthcare and pharmaceutical enterprises.

I have experience in AI product research and development; in the domain such as Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision & Conversational Agents.

Before Indegene, I was working with Mindstix Software Labs as Solutions Architect Data Science, developing Machine Learning solutions for the clients.

As Software Engineering is improving steadily, to keep up with the industry, I have also completed 159+ courses related to Machine Learning, Software Engineering, etc. from Udemy, Coursera, Datacamp, & LinkedIn Learning.

Professional Experience

Sr Data Analyst - Indegene Inc

IMC AUTO AUTHORING 🖵 PYTHON, TENSORFLOW, NER

May 2020 - Present

· Meta Data Auto tagging, NER extraction, Layout recommendation etc

Data Science Solution Architect - Mindstix Software Labs

VMware Inc

GENIE SPEAKER RECOGNITION - PYTHON, TENSORFLOW, CNN, RESNET, ANN INDEXING, VLAD

Dec 2018 - Present

- This is a text-independent speaker recognition system built using deep neural network. It is based on ResNet architecture with NetVLAD & GhostVLAD layers. This is a three-stage system consists mainly of Development, Enrollment & Verification stage.
- In the Development stage, I have created new modified thin ResNet architecture with 34 layers & 3 million parameters. It is trained end-to-end for speaker recognition on 10GB of speaker data for 8K Classes using Adam optimizer with additive margin softmax (AM-Softmax) loss.
- In the Enrollment stage, created a speaker-specific model using embeddings extracted from previously trained model. In the Verification stage, used high dimensional Approximate Nearest Neighbour Indexing to predict nearest match for test input.

Machine Learning Engineer - Mindstix Software Labs

VMware Inc.

GENIE DIGITAL ASSISTANT 🖵 PYTHON, TENSORFLOW, KERAS, LSTM, RASA

Feb 2018 - Aug 2019

- This application is a digital chatbot assistant helping customers to get their issues resolved. Built the **Natural Language Understanding** framework for entity recognition, intent classification & dialogue management using **LSTM architecture** along with other libraries like **Spacy, Rasa**, etc.
- Created Frequently Asked Question service using Universal Sentence Encoder

Computer Vision Engineer - Mindstix Software Labs

Estée Lauder Companies Inc.

FOUNDATION RECOMMENDATION ENGINE 🖵 PYTHON, OPENCY, COMPUTER VISION, DEEP LEARNING, TENSORFLOW

Feb 2018 - Dec 2019

- Created a new Fully Convolutional Network using AlexNet architecture with a domain-specific loss function.
- Using developed algorithm, color corrected image is generated basis which skin tone of a person is calculated using statistical methods.
- Built **Product recommendations** based on the user's preferences & extracted skin tone.

Machine Learning Engineer - Coriolis Technologies

LICENSE PLATE RECOGNITION SYSTEM 🖵 CNN, OPENCV, PYTHON, OBJECT DETECTION, CLASSIFICATION, YOLO

March 2016 - Feb 2018

- An Automatic License Plate Recognition System using Deep Learning algorithms for Indian vehicles.
- I have **trained 5 different YOLO CNN Networks** for vehicle detection, prediction of the bounding box for License Plate, character segmentation, alphabet recognition & digit recognition.

May 30, 2020 Ishwar Sawale · Résumé 1

Skills

Languages & Frameworks

Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch, Python, Django, Flask, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, GO, Ruby, Rails

Machine Learning

Computer Vision

 $Regression\ Algorithms,\ Decision\ Trees,\ SVM,\ Navie\ Bayes,\ kNN,\ K-Means,\ Random\ Forest\ etc.$

Deep Learning CNN, ResNet, DenseNet, Inception, MobileNet, RNN, LSTM, Chatbot

Classification, Object Detection, Segmentation, Color Correction, Image Processing

Education

Diploma in Big Data Analytics

Pune, India

CDAC-ACTS Pune(70%)

Aug 2015 - Feb. 2016

Bachelor of Engineering

Pune, India

SINHGAD ACADEMY OF ENGINEERING, PUNE (69.33%)

Aug. 2011 - May. 2014

Courses List

PylmageSearch

· PylmageSearch Gurus Graduate by PylmageSearch

Coursera

- · Mathematics for Machine Learning, a 3-course specialization by Imperial College London
- TensorFlow in Practice Specialization by deeplearning.ai
- · Structuring Machine Learning Projects by deeplearning.ai
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning by deeplearning.ai
- · Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization by deeplearning.ai
- · Recommender Systems: Evaluation and Metrics
- · Nearest Neighbor Collaborative Filtering
- Matrix Factorization and Advanced Techniques
- · Introduction to Recommender Systems: Non-Personalized and Content-Based
- Fundamentals of Digital Image and Video Processing by Northwestern University
- PCA by Imperial College London
- Multivariate Calculus by Imperial College London
- · Linear Algebra by Imperial College London
- How Google does Machine Learning by Google Cloud

Datacamp

- Machine Learning with Python Track
- · Data Scientist with Python Track
- Image Processing with Python Track
- Data Manipulation with Python Track
- Data Analyst with Python Track
- Importing & Cleaning Data with Python Track
- Data Scientist with R Track
- Data Analyst with R Track
- Importing & Cleaning Data with R Track
- Machine Learning with R Track